It smells so good!
好香哦
I wish I could eat it straight away.
真想直接吃呢
Good morning!
早安
Want some breakfast, Rin?
小凛也要吃早餐吗
Canapé.
开胃饼
A type of bread sliced thinly and toasted until crispy,
是一种将面包切成薄片 以小火烘烤成饼干
then spread with cream cheese, topped with ham,
并在上面涂奶油奶酪 放上生火腿
and drizzled with olive oil.
再淋上适量的橄榄油
And there you have it,
生火腿奶油奶酪开胃饼
"HAM AND CREAM CHEESE CANAPÉ" ham and cream cheese canapé.
马上就完成了
It's delicious!
好好吃
Can't believe we're indulging in such luxury so early in the morning.
居然一大早就如此享受
Can I have another?
我可以再吃一块吗
Help yourself!
尽量吃吧
You mentioned a famous suspension bridge in Sumatakyo.
之前听你说 寸又峡有一座特别有名的吊桥
You mean the Yume (Dream) Suspension Bridge?
你是说梦之吊桥吧
Suspension bridge…
吊桥…
If you want to go there,
抚子要去的话
you'll have to catch the bus that comes in an hour.
就要搭一个小时后的公交车
If you miss it,
如果没赶上那班公交车
you won't be able to go.
可能就暂时去不了了
The bus an hour from now?
一个小时候的公交车吗
No problem…
没问题…
It's a 39-minute walk to the bus stop.
从这里走到公交车站 就要走39分钟哦
We'll take care of the clean-up.
这边我们来善后就好
Thank you very much.
太感谢了
Even at a time like this, you're still a glutton.
即便在这种时候 你还是一样贪吃呢
LAID-BACK CAMP SEASON 3
《摇曳露营△ (第三季)》
EPISODE 6: SEE YOU AGAIN
(第6话 那么 改天再见)
"WELCOME TO SUMATAKYO HOT SPRINGS" The bike girls.
(欢迎光临寸又峡温泉) 机车组
It's about 11 kilometres from the campsite to the suspension bridge.
从露营场到吊桥大约要骑11公里
Sumatakyo.
寸又峡
We're here!
到了
There was an uphill climb,
虽然要爬坡
but the roads were nice and made it a pretty smooth ride.
但路况很好 骑得超轻松的呢
Well, this is a popular tourist area.
毕竟这里是知名的观光景点啊
SUMATA VILLAGE
(寸又庄)
MOTORCYCLE PARKING, 200 YEN EACH PLEASE PUT THE MONEY IN THE CAN, THANK YOU
(机车一台200圆) (请把钱投入罐子里 谢谢)
Excuse me.
不好意思
We'd like to park our bikes outside.
我们要暂时把机车停在外面
Go right ahead.
好 请便
The sight of cats and dogs
放养的小狗小猫晒太阳的模样
basking in the sun is truly healing.
看着真疗愈呢
I can relate.
我懂
PICKLES, WILD VEGETABLES, SUMATAKYO TOUR
(腌制物 山菜珍味 寸又峡之旅)
How free-spirited.
真随兴
By the way, where is Nadeshiko?
话说回来 抚子跑去哪里了呀?
We agreed to meet in front of the guesthouse.
明明说好在民宿前会合的
She's over there, Aya.
小绫 她在那里
This potato mochi is so good! It's soft and gooey!
土豆麻糬好好吃哦 软软嫩嫩的
She's already eating.
居然已经开吃了
She's a free-spirited one too.
这家伙也很随兴呢
After successfully meeting up,
顺利会合后
they headed to the most famous suspension bridge in Oigawa.
马上前往大井川最有名的吊桥
Let's go!
走吧
However, just as they were about to leave,
正当她们要出发时
their attention was caught by a foot bath café.
又被足汤咖啡厅吸引了
I'm surprised there's a café here.
这种地方居然还有咖啡厅啊
Foot bath café.
足汤咖啡厅
The gelato is great!
义式冰淇淋真好吃
The cheesecake's delicious too.
奶酪蛋糕也很赞呢
The foot bath is so relaxing.
足汤也超舒服的
Put your hands in and you'll feel even warmer.
把手一起放进去 会变得更温暖哦
So warm…
好暖和
It's cold today.
毕竟今天也很冷嘛
I want to soak my whole body in it.
好想就这样把整个身体泡进去
Stop that line of thought.
快住脑
This isn't the place for that.
这不是身为人该做的事
Huh? Aren't you the girl from the train?
咦 这不是之前那位小妹妹吗
Oh? It's you ladies!
咦 大姐姐们
These are the ladies who sat next to me on the ABT train.
这两位是我搭ABT式列车时 坐在我旁边的大姐姐们
Hello.
你们好
We even saw the clink-clink.
昨天我们还一起看了噗哔哐呢
Clink-clink?
噗哔哐?
So you guys stayed in Sumatakyo?
大姐姐们住在寸又峡啊
Yeah.
对呀
How was camping in Ichishiro?
在市代那里露营 感觉怎么样啊?
It was so much fun!
超好玩的
Are you two also heading to the Dream Suspension Bridge?
两位等等也要去梦之吊桥吗
We're heading home now.
我们准备回家啦
We checked out the suspension bridge yesterday.
吊桥昨天已经去过了
We went for a walk in Ikawa and only arrived here in the evening.
我们先在井川那边散步 傍晚才到这边
All right. To the suspension bridge we go!
很好 去吊桥吧
The sun was already setting when she mentioned wanting to go to the bridge.
结果夕阳都快下山了 这个人才说要去吊桥走走
We ended up halfway when the sun set.
最后走到一半 夕阳就下山了
We had to rely on our phones' flashlights
只能在黑暗中
to make our way back in the dark.
靠着手机的手电筒勉强走回来
There wasn't a single street lamp to be found.
没想到那边居然一盏路灯都没有
You guys were lucky you didn't encounter any bears.
幸好没有遇到熊呢
But the view
不过
from the suspension bridge was beautiful. So, it was all worth it.
吊桥那边的景色很漂亮 没有白走一趟呢
I'm really looking forward to it!
好期待哦
Then let's finish up…
那就赶紧吃完
and head out!
准备出发吧
You girls take care of yourselves.
路上小心哦
We will.
好的
YUME SUSPENSION BRIDGE BEAUTY SPRING
(梦之吊桥 美人汤)
YUME SUSPENSION BRIDGE, HIRYU BRIDGE MT. KUROHOSHI ENTRANCE
(梦之吊桥 飞龙桥) (前黑法师岳登山口)
PLEASE USE THESE WALKING STICKS
(欢迎使用登山杖)
Duel at Ganryu Island.
岩流岛之战
You know,
话说回来
you really have a knack for making friends with anyone, Nadeshiko.
抚子真的跟任何人都能变成朋友呢
Absolutely…
没错…
Really?
有吗
Well, you're like a puppy.
毕竟抚子是狗狗嘛
Likes everyone. Loves walks.
每个人都喜欢 超喜欢散步
Totally.
我懂
Come to think of it,
这么说起来
back when I was in Year 1 or 2,
印象中小一还小二的时候
I remember going shopping with Nadeshiko's family once.
我有跟抚子一家外出买过东西
Nadeshiko disappeared out of the blue.
当时我们以为抚子突然消失了
Oh no, where's Nadeshiko?
哎呀 抚子呢?
Did she get lost?
是迷路了吗
Who's that kid?
那孩子是谁呀?
Found her.
找到了
When we found her at last, she was playing with some kid from another family.
后来才发现她混进了 一个完全不认识的家庭
Did that really happen?
有发生过这种事吗
It's probably because something like that has happened too many times
或许就是经历过太多次这种状况
that Sakura-san keeps such a close eye on Nadeshiko all the time.
樱小姐才会时时刻刻盯着抚子吧
Sarunami Bridge.
猿并桥
It is said that it is named so because the monkeys that live in the mountains
听说是因为住在山里的猴子 都会走这座桥去寸又峡温泉
use this bridge to go to the Sumatakyo Hot Spring.
所以才叫这个名字
So the monkeys here actually soak in hot springs?
这里的猴子果然也会泡温泉吗
Maybe.
说不定哦
That's a therapeutic image.
感觉很疗愈呢
It's a monkey!
是猴子
Oh, you're right.
真的耶
We can see the Yume Suspension Bridge!
可以看到梦之吊桥咯
Finally!
终于到了
Yume Suspension Bridge.
梦之吊桥
The bridge only allows one-way traffic,
桥只能单向通行
so after crossing, we have to take a big detour to come back.
所以走到对岸后 要绕一大圈才能回来
There really aren't many tourists when you avoid peak times.
果然错开高峰时期 就没什么游客了呢
We can take our time to cross it. That's great.
能悠哉地走过去 真是太棒了
The river is such a beautiful colour.
河水的颜色好漂亮哦
But it's still scary to look down.
不过往下看的话 还是会有点害怕呢
It's 8 metres high.
总高8米
And it sways a lot when you reach the middle…!
而且走到正中间时 桥晃得好厉害
Aren't you guys scared at all?
你们不会怕吗
Well,
毕竟我们
we survived the bridge of death.
昨天已经走过死亡之桥了啊
This is a piece of cake.
这根本不算什么
Oh, right.
对了
I looked it up yesterday.
昨天我查了一下
There's a suspension bridge in the mountains here
这边的深山里 好像有一座比畑薙还可怕的吊桥哦
What? That suspension bridge wasn't the craziest?
呃 原来那座吊桥还不是最强的吗
"MUSOU SUSPENSION BRIDGE" With a total length of 144 metres
(梦想吊桥) 全长144米
and a height of 83 metres,
总高83米
it was initially built for the convenience of forestry work,
起初为了便于林业工作而建
but it's now widely known as Japan's scariest suspension bridge.
目前作为日本 最可怕的吊桥广为人知
83 metres?
总高83米的话
Doesn't that make it three times taller than the Hatanagi Suspension Bridge?
不就快比畑薙大吊桥高3倍了吗
And that bridge's deteriorating.
而且听说那座桥还在不断老化
It could collapse at any moment.
随时都有可能掉下去哦
Sounds like some sort of Russian roulette suspension bridge!
那是什么俄罗斯轮盘吊桥啊
Due to severe damage, the Musou Suspension Bridge
由于梦想吊桥现在毁损严重
is no longer accessible.
已经无法过桥了
Oh, is that a dam over there?
咦 那是水坝吗
It seems like it.
应该是吧
We did pass by what looked like
刚才要过来这里时
an administrative building on the way here.
也有看到一栋像管理处的房子
Yeah, we did.
确实有看到呢
Nagashima, Ikawa, Hatanagi.
长岛 井川 畑薙
We've crossed many suspension bridges
看来我们不仅走了很多吊桥
and dams.
也去了很多座水坝呢
We did.
是啊
So that's Oma Dam.
原来那是大间水坝啊
That was close!
吓死我了
That was scary!
好危险啊
Better not use your phone while on the bridge,
在吊桥上滑手机
or you might just fall into the river.
小心掉进河川里哦
You're right.
说得也是呢
The river must be filled
这底下的河川
with phones from all the people who were too distracted trying to get "the shot".
肯定堆满了 为了拍网美照而掉下去的手机吧
Not exactly eco-friendly…
感觉对环境超不友好的
Smile!
要拍咯
What kind of pose is this?
这是什么姿势啊
We got off the suspension bridge,
明明已经走下吊桥了
but I still can't feel my legs.
但还是有种摇摇晃晃的感觉
I feel you…
没错…
TAKE YOUR TIME AND REST AS YOU GO TOTAL: 340 STEPS
(一边休息一边往上走吧 总共340阶)
You can do it, Aya!
小绫 加油
You got this.
加油
Is this what they call a miracle in times of crisis?
这就是所谓的绝地逢生吗
Never expected to find ourselves climbing up a mountain out of nowhere.
没想到走着走着 居然就开始爬山了
After all that walking,
在走了许多路后
it was time for some lunch.
先吃个午餐
"YAMASASA SOBA, MATSUZAKE HONTEN" Welcome.
(山笹荞麦面 松竹本铺) 欢迎光临
Anything you'd recommend?
有什么推荐的吗
The stream soba
这个溪流荞麦面
is our signature dish.
是我最推荐的料理哦
Then I'll go with that.
那我就点那个
Me too.
我也是
I'll have the same.
我也要一样的
Stream soba is delicious!
溪流荞麦面 超好吃
THE BATH IS OPEN TODAY
(今日可以泡汤)
Nothing beats soaking in a hot spring after all that walking.
逛完一圈再来泡个温泉 感觉特别舒服呢
Right.
就是说啊
This is bliss…
太幸福了…
This Beauty Spring is said to have amazing skincare effects.
这个美人汤可是一种 美肤效果绝佳的温泉
Rumour has it that anyone who bathes here turns into a beauty.
听说在这里泡过澡的人 全都会变成美女呢
A while ago, a group of middle-aged men on a biking trip
前阵子也有一群骑车旅行的大叔 顺便过来这里泡温泉
After they came out, they all turned into beauties.
结果出来后 大家都变成美女了
What kind of transformative hot spring is that?
那是什么变性温泉啊
What's the plan after this, Aya?
小绫等等有什么安排吗
Going to Senzu to buy souvenirs
等一下要去千头买伴手礼
and then head to see the last suspension bridge.
接着再去看最后一座吊桥
Guess this trip is coming to an end.
那这趟旅行也差不多要结束了呢
I half-soloed this trip,
因为这次有一半的时间 都是单独行动
so it felt very different.
感觉跟以往有些不同
But having the chance to relax and take my time was really nice.
不过有机会悠哉自在一下 还是让人很开心呢
I'm feeling pretty exhausted though.
我倒是觉得很累呢
That's because you chose the more challenging path.
那是因为你选了一条难走的路吧
SUMATAKYO HOT SPRING BUS STOP
(寸又峡温泉公交车发车站)
We'll see you in Senzu.
那么 千头见
Drive safely.
你们骑车小心点哦
Let's go, then.
我们也走吧
Let's.
走吧
You take care too.
你也要保重哦
In mid-March,
3月中旬
even though it's early spring, the weather remains chilly.
虽说已经进入早春 但天气依旧寒冷
Riding a bike during this time
此时骑车的话
makes the cold wind feel even more bone-chilling.
寒风会显得更加冰冷刺骨
That's why bikers eagerly anticipate taking detours
所以骑士们都会特别期待
I still feel warm.
身体还暖乎乎的
After soaking in the hot spring, their bodies feel warm and cosy.
泡进温泉中 等身体充分暖和起来后
However, it's crucial to wait until the body is thoroughly warmed up
要等待身上的红晕退去
and any redness has subsided before drying off sweat and putting on clothes.
并仔细擦干汗水 才能穿上衣服
If you get dressed immediately after leaving the bath,
如果从浴池出来就马上穿上衣服
the skin inside the clothes will continue to sweat,
衣服内的皮肤会持续冒汗
causing the body to cool down again.
反而会导致身体再次变冷
Ayano and Rin, who had just set off,
忘记这一点的绫乃和凛
forgot about this…
才刚启程没多久
It's freezing!
超冷的
…and started shivering.
就开始瑟瑟发抖了
Rin, I see the last suspension bridge!
小凛 可以看到最后一座吊桥了
Rin! Aya!
小凛 小绫
SHIOGO SUSPENSION BRIDGE (KOI KANAHASHI)
(盐乡吊桥 恋金桥)
Shiogo Suspension Bridge.
盐乡吊桥
Woah!
好猛
This suspension bridge hangs right above the residential area.
这座吊桥悬挂在民宅的正上方耶
It's different from the suspension bridges we walked on before.
跟我们之前走过的吊桥不太一样呢
This one feels scarier than the Yume Suspension Bridge.
这里好像比梦之吊桥还可怕
This suspension bridge is 10 metres off the ground.
这座吊桥总高10米
About the same as Yume Suspension Bridge.
应该跟梦之吊桥差不多吧
Whether the ground below is solid or water also affects the scary factor.
底下是地面还是水面 或许也会影响走起来的感觉呢
After all, if you fall off the bridge
毕竟从桥上掉下去时
and there's water below, you might still have a chance.
如果底下是水 或许还能捡回一命
I see what you mean.
我好像懂你的意思了
But, the view from here is really nice.
不过 这座吊桥的景色真不错呢
The scenery is pretty nice.
视野确实很不错呢
Hello.
你们好
I see.
原来如此
The middle part is built wider for the times
为了错开迎面而来的人 有些地方的桥面才会比较宽敞啊
Opposite directions…
迎面而来的人…
If someone had been coming from the opposite direction
如果在走畑薙大吊桥时
while we were crossing Hatanagi Suspension Bridge…
对面刚好也有人要过来的话
Hatanagi Suspension Bridge left you two with some serious trauma, huh?
你们是不是对畑薙大吊桥 留下阴影了啊?
Hey! It's dangerous to run on the suspension bridge!
喂 在吊桥上奔跑很危险耶
Kids really do fear nothing…
真…真是初生之犊不畏虎啊
Turn back here.
在此折返
"LOVE BELL" If we keep going forward,
(恋爱钟) 再继续往前走的话
it seems we'll reach a campsite ahead.
好像有一个露营场哦
SAKURA
(樱)
Was… was that a steam train just now?
刚…刚才那是蒸汽火车吧
I forgot to take a photo of it!
忘…忘记拍照了
Okay.
很好
I'll get my dad to photoshop one in.
之后再叫爸爸帮我P一台 蒸汽火车吧
"HERE" Right here.
(这附近) 就P在这里
You're really going to do that, Nadeshiko?
这样你就满足了吗 抚子
So, it seems like there's a steam train
原来大井川这边
passing through Oigawa almost every day.
几乎每天都会有蒸汽火车经过啊
I had no idea.
我都不知道
Even the regular trains are retro.
普通列车都是复古风
"CLINK-CLINK" You can also see steam trains
(噗哔哐) 还可以看到蒸汽火车和观光小火车
Oigawa is truly a paradise for train enthusiasts!
大井川简直就是铁道迷的圣地啊
When did you become a train enthusiast?
你什么时候变成铁道迷了啊
I'm not. It's just, after riding the ABT train,
没啦 就是搭了ABT式列车后
I'm starting to think these retro-style trains are really cute.
开始觉得复古的列车好像满可爱的
So I guess that sparked an interest.
因此产生了一点兴趣
Plus,
而且
taking a train all the way to a campsite
像这次这样一路搭火车到露营场
is actually quite fun.
其实也满有趣的
If Rin is a bike camper,
如果说小凛是骑机车露营者
I'm going to be a train camper.
那我打算成为一个搭电车露营者
Sounds good.
听起来挺不错的嘛
Does it?
真的吗
Even though I'm looking forward to moving to Yamanashi,
虽然很期待去山梨
I won't have anyone I know there.
但我在那边一个认识的人都没有
That makes me feel kind of lonely.
果然还是觉得有点寂寞呢
Oh, come on.
真是的
With your personality,
以你的性格 就算换了一个新环境
you'll make new friends in no time.
肯定也很快就会交到朋友了
Don't worry about it.
你就放心吧
You think so?
是这样吗
-See? I was right. -Oh, right!
-这不是跟我说的一样 -对了
-You already have a good friend. -I should buy that on my way home…
-马上就交到好朋友了吗 -回程途中绕去买那个再回家吧
All right, then…
那么
Aya?
小绫?
The train should be arriving soon.
电车应该快来了
I should get going too.
我也差不多该出发了
We'll go camping together again… right?
之后还能一起去露营…对吧?
Anytime.
随时都可以去哦
After all, I'll be riding my bike.
毕竟我会骑机车啊
If it's an invitation from you two,
只要是你们两个的邀请
I'll go wherever!
无论要去哪里 我都奉陪
Aya…
小绫
"SHIOGO SUSPENSION BRIDGE" Aya!
(盐乡吊桥)
I really don't want to go home yet!
果然还是不想现在就回家啊
"ZONE OF DESPAIR" Just the thought of riding for two hours
(毫无干劲区) 一想到要在那条
on that seemingly endless straight road back home
宛如没有尽头的笔直道路上 骑两小时才能回家
drains all my energy!
我就瞬间失去干劲了
Nadeshiko, I don't want to go home…
抚子 我还不想回家啦
I remember going through that when I went to Hamamatsu at the end of last year.
我年末去滨松时也走过一次
I completely understand how you feel.
完全能理解你的心情
"EMPTY YOUR MIND" Riding continuously on flat ground
(心无杂念) 不仅一直骑在平地上
with the same scenery the entire way,
风景也大同小异
it's like a form of Zen meditation.
一直骑在那种路上 简直就是禅道修行
Meditation?
修行?
I've got it!
我知道了
Let's take on another suspension bridge!
那就再去挑战一座吊桥吧
Let's do it!
走吧…
Another?
再一座…
But we're already downstream. There might not be any around here.
但这里已经是下游 好像没有吊桥咯
Don't worry.
放心吧
I saw one yesterday on the sightseeing sign at Kanaya Station.
我昨天在金谷站的观光导览区 刚好看到了一座
HORAI BRIDGE
(蓬莱桥)
Horai Bridge.
蓬莱桥
As the world's longest wooden pedestrian bridge,
作为世界第一长的木造天桥
it has been certified by the Guinness World Records.
获得吉尼斯世界纪录认证
It's a bit different from a suspension bridge,
虽然跟吊桥有点不一样
but it has its own charm.
但这座桥也别有一番风味呢
All right. It's time to go home.
好 回家吧
If I stay any longer,
再继续拖下去
it'll get dark, and that's no good for driving.
万一天色变暗 骑车也会比较危险
Sorry for keeping you both for so long.
抱歉 让你们陪我这么久
It's no big deal.
这也没什么啦
Aya, let's find some time soon to go camping together again!
小绫 最近再找时间一起去露营吧
Even if I can't do "soon",
虽然没办法马上再出来玩
I'll go all the way to Yamanashi to find you guys next time.
但下次我会骑到山梨去找你的
Aya.
小绫
Until we see each other again.
那么 改天见
Yes, yes…
好啦…
Make sure you tell me when you reach home.
你们到家后 记得报个平安哦
I'll be worried.
不然我会担心的
Okay…
好…
And don't take the wrong train, Nadeshiko.
你也不要搭错车咯 抚子
It's 9 PM already?
已经9点了吗
I accidentally stayed out too late.
不小心拖太晚了
I'm home now. I'm exhausted…
我到家了 超累的
Rin made it home too.
小凛也到家了啊
Glad to hear that.
辛苦了
I'll be home in another ten minutes.
我再10分钟左右就到家咯
I made it home too, barely hanging on riding on National Route 1.
我也到家了 在国一上骑到快挂掉
Good, good.
很好…
After crossing this bridge, I'll be home.
走过这座桥 就到家了
And that will mark the end of this camping trip.
而这场露营也即将落幕
But I'll always have these memories.
但回忆会永远留存在心中呢
Where should we go next time?
下次要去哪里好呢
I'm back.
我回来了
Welcome home.
欢迎回家
Nadeshiko, you're back a bit late.
抚子 这次回来得有点晚哦
Sorry.
抱歉…
I took a detour to Kakegawa on my way back,
因为我回程搭电车去了挂川一趟
so it took me a while.
多花了不少时间
Kakegawa?
挂川?
"SUPER TASTY 100% BEEF HAMBURG STEAK" I went to buy this.
(超好吃100%汉堡排) 我特地去买了这个
Because you said you haven't had this in a while.
因为姐姐你之前说很久没吃了
You can order that online, you know?
那个汉堡排其实可以用网购的哦
Really?
真的吗
Hold up!
给我等一下
Have you guys completely forgotten about us?
你们是不是完全忘记 我们的存在了?
Long time no see! I'm Chiaki Ohgaki.
好久不见 我是大垣千明
Hey, I can see you guys.
喂 你们都露出来咯
The next episode is finally going to be about our camping misadventures!
下集终于要讲到我们的 自暴自弃露营了
Don't miss it!
一定要看哦
NEXT EPISODE: TRUTH OR LIES, REALITY OR FICTION, MEMORIES OF CAMPING
(下集 真真假假回忆露营)
WHEN ENJOYING CAMPING, BE SURE TO FOLLOW THE RULES
(享受露营时…) (务必遵守露营场和其设施的规定)
DON'T FORGET TO PUT OUT YOUR CAMPFIRE AND DISPOSE OF YOUR GARBAGE.
(别忘了灭火和带走垃圾)
TEMPERATURES CAN CHANGE QUICKLY, SO CHECK THE WEATHER FORECAST BEFOREHAND.
(由于气温可能会急速变化) (记得事先确认天气预报)
WEAR WARM CLOTHING IF NECESSARY TO PREVENT COLD.
(必要时穿着保暖衣物防寒)